Sahil Sharma

Mandi

sahilsharma7936 a4y@indeedemail.com

+91 98164 76777

Innovative Civil Engineer with proficiency in planning and execution, Lead team from front, Excellent blueprint interpreting skills. Experienced in preparing tender filing and designs, preliminary designs and detailed design structural drawings. Experienced working with HP.PWD, HP.IPH and Forest Dept. Experience in prestressing detailed drawings. Bridge and Buildings alignment drawings and geotechnical profile. Knowledge of construction methods and construction sequences in civil structural constructions above or below the ground. Sound knowledge of engineering software's. Well familiar with IRC, Indian Standards.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Civil Site Engineer

Thakur Construction's Private Limited September 2020 to Present

- Construction of Flood Protection Walls over Baspa River, Sangla, Kinnuar (HP)
- Construction of Flood Protection Wall over Beas River, Kullu (HP)
- Construction of Flood Protection Wall in Thunag Bazar (HP)

Site Engineer

CK infra Ltd. February 2022 to June 2022

Internship (Trainee)

Afcons, Pandoh-Takoli June 2019 to August 2019

Construction of Highway Tunnel

1. Degree in Civil Engineering

Junior Engineer

Sunworld Arista - Noida, Uttar Pradesh September 2013 to January 2015

Construction of commercial buildings, high rise buildings and other amenities involved in the Project.

- Supplier and Vendor Management
- Client Relations and Management- CRM Tool
- Interactions with RERA Authority, U.P
- Design Drawing Executions
- Experience in preparing Bill of Quantities

Education

Bachelor's in Civil engineering

Abhilashi University April 2017 to August 2020

Diploma in Architectural Assistant in ship

Govt. Polytechnic Sunder nagar June 2010 to July 2013

Skills / IT Skills

- STAAD Pro. (Structure, Modelling and Analysis)
- Budgeting
- Project Management
- Site Layout
- AutoCAD (2007, 2009, 2010 & 2013), with sound knowledge of 2D and 3D modelling
- MS-Office, Windows 7 & XP Other Responsibilities
- Project Management and Scheduling, tracking all data related to project, Handling business development and technical activities with various govt. department (PWD, IPH and Forest Dept.) Key Responsibility Handled
- Prepare drawings for construction methodology with alternative methods according to different site conditions and construction sequences for precast and cast-in-situ super structure.
- Experience in valuation and Cost estimation.
- · Purchase and Vendor Management
- Tender Documentation
- EOI Documents, RFQs, RFP, Contract Negotiation and evaluation of Bids.
- To prepare Volumetric drawings in AutoCAD 3d for quality calculation. Key Projects Undertaken
- Construction of Flood Protection Walls over Baspa River, Project of IPH Deptt. Sangla, Kinnuar (HP) Project Estimation
- 7,30,000,00 Design and Construction of Flood walls while managing and supervising labour count above 500. Project involves design activities, contract managements, vendor management. Engagement in handling and maintenance related matters for Over Head Machines/Other construction related tools.
- Construction of Flood Protection Wall over Beas River, Project of IPH Deptt. Kullu (HP) Project Estimation- 2,10,000,00
- Construction of Flood Protection Wall in Thunag Bazar (Siraj, Mandi), Project of IPH Deptt. (HP) Project Estimation
- 7,0513097.00
- · Communication skills
- English
- Computer skills
- AutoCAD